Sachin yadav

 ♦ Bangalore City, India
 sachin11061997@gmail.com
 +917057480940
 in/sachin-yadav-web3/

https://5ach1n.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

Technical Lead with 4 years of experience in web3 development. Proven ability to develop solutions for large scale projects and lead a team of developers to success. Experienced in driving projects from concept to completion, while meeting tight deadlines and customer expectations. Applying for the position of Technical Lead / CTO

EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead

consciousleap TM

April 2023 - Present, Dubai, UAE

- · As a tech lead, I oversaw the development of a full website and application from scratch, managing a team of three developers and setting coding standards and best practices.
- · I facilitated communication between team members, managed workloads, conducted code reviews, and provided mentorship, resulting in a successful launch of the project on time and within budget.
- Developed a website and application from conception to completion, increased team productivity by 40%, increased code quality by 45%, and achieved project goals on schedule, resulting in a successful launch.

Full Stack WEB3 Engineer

Platter Inc.

December 2022 - April 2023, Bangalore, India

- Demonstrated expertise in developing and deploying decentralized applications (dApps) using blockchain technologies, including creating smart contracts and integrating them into dApps to enable blockchain functionality.
- Designed and developed user interfaces for dApps using web3 libraries, integrated web3 wallets, and utilized decentralized storage solutions. Collaborated with designers and product managers to create user-centered experiences for dApps and integrated third-party APIs and services.
- Developed server-side logic for dApps using back-end technologies and utilized DevOps tools and practices to deploy and manage the applications.

Full stack Developer

Gigaverse pvt. ltd.

July 2021 - December 2022, Pune, India

- Managed and led technical product teams in the development and execution of protocol strategies, designs, and implementations.
- · Created bespoke bots to meet the specific needs of Gigaverse and its clients in defining and launching their instances of the protocol.
- Facilitated goal setting, planning, retrospectives, and backlog grooming to ensure project milestones and objectives attained for website code and smart contracts.

Product Developer

PhenomPeople Inc.

January 2022 - April 2022, Hyderabad, India

- · Conducted in-depth business discussions with senior management and provided key market data from various sources to inform business decisions.
- Built charts and graphs to visualize data and met the operational data needs of the marketing team.
- · Conducted thorough business analysis using tools such as MySql, Python, Beautifulsoup, and Numpy to identify system connections and develop new bot scripts, procedures, and guidelines.

PROJECTS

consciousleap website [LARAVEL]

consciousleap TM · April 2023 - Present

- Developed the consciousleap website framework using Laravel, created custom-tailored modules leveraging various tools and technologies for an interactive platform, and optimized website performance of the website for a 50% reduction in loading time.
- Improved customer experience by developing improved usability features, leveraging version control and bug tracking systems, and offering 24-hour response to customer inquiries.

Platter Alpha Product

Platter Inc • December 2022 - Present

- Developed a portfolio DApp from scratch using MERN stack, providing an intuitive and user-friendly interface for users to manage their cryptocurrency portfolios.
- · Integrated multiple cryptocurrency exchanges and wallets into the DApp, enabling users to track their holdings across multiple platforms in one place.
- Developed a backend API using Node.js and Express to fetch real-time market data and user account balances, optimizing the DApp for performance.

Python bots scripting

PhenomPeople pvt. ltd. · January 2022 - April 2022

- Developed several Telegram marketing bots under Gigaverse to automate customer conversion and connect them with relevant services.
- · Utilized MS Excel-sheet with Python and Numpy embedded application to create the bots.
- · Implemented web scraping scripts to collect relevant WhatsApp data for targeted marketing using technologies like Selenium and Beautiful Soup (BS4).

Verified Smart contracts & CryptoCurrency Development

Gigaverse pvt. ltd. • August 2021 - December 2021

- Developed and deployed a verified smart contract for virtual currency \$GIGS on the Binance Smart Chain with essential functionalities.
- Integrated NFT candymachine using the Metaplex standard contracts for direct NFT listings with verified sources.
- · Utilized Solidity and Remix IDE to develop secure contracts that met platform requirements.

INVOLVEMENT

President

Sinhgad · Toastmasters Club · March 2022 - March 2023

- Implemented new operating plans that increased company profitability by 40% through cost and operational efficiency, built new partnerships which increased customer base by 20% and generated new revenue streams of over 3 lakh
- · Developed and lead multi-year strategic plan that integrated product, service, and operational initiatives with long-term financial goals.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Science

Minor in information Technology • Pune University • Pune ,India • 2021 • 9.89 CGPA

SKILLS

Blockchain (Ethereum, Binance Smart Chain, Solana, zk rollups), Smart contracts (Solidity, Vyper), Web3 (Web3.js, Ethers.js), Decentralized storage (IPFS, Arweave), Stack (MERN /MEAN /LAMP), Frontend (HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, React.js, Vue.js, Typescript, Angular), Backend (Node.js, Express), Databases (MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL), DevOps (Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, Azure), 3D Render(Three.js, D3.js)